<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Zak's Tech Notes</title><link>https://notes.zakhassan.me/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Zak's Tech Notes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 15:00:18 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://notes.zakhassan.me/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dns 101</title><link>https://notes.zakhassan.me/posts/dns-101/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 15:00:18 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://notes.zakhassan.me/posts/dns-101/</guid><description>Introduction to DNS: Simple way to explain DNS is think of a phone book and your mapping names to phone numbers. DNS maps urls google.com to an ip address. DNS can be considered a distributed database with partition zones and domain names are paths in an inverted tree. ICAAN runs the root domain and verisign runs the nodes under com. Delegation is the process to allow an organization to assign control of subdomains.</description></item><item><title>Knative Introduction</title><link>https://notes.zakhassan.me/posts/knative-introduction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 14:44:11 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://notes.zakhassan.me/posts/knative-introduction/</guid><description>Introduction The knative project is very interesting as I work on an always on ML Service called log anomaly detector. One idea came to mind is to perform the machine learning encoding on logs that come in and have it scale to zero when no data is streamed in. Also to have the system scale up as the demand increases. If I was running something like this on the cloud where I’m charged by the minute then I’d use serverless as a way to cut costs.</description></item><item><title>Profiling Python Programs</title><link>https://notes.zakhassan.me/posts/profiling-python-programs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 14:42:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://notes.zakhassan.me/posts/profiling-python-programs/</guid><description>To run the python profiling code run the following:
. venv/bin/activate
Will contain your env vars for LAD source .env
python -m cProfile -o ~/prof.out app.py &amp;gt; cprof.txt
snakeviz ~/prof.out
Make A Graph Of Your Program: gprof2dot -f pstats ~/prof.out -o graph.dot
dot -Tpng graph.dot -o graph.png</description></item><item><title>Azure Devops Services</title><link>https://notes.zakhassan.me/posts/azure-devops-services/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 11:59:44 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://notes.zakhassan.me/posts/azure-devops-services/</guid><description>Introduction Wanted to share some notes I made as I have done a first look at Azure. Coming from AWS background, Azure seems like a promising platform to develop on. I wanted to share some notes from self study below:
Azure DevOps Services: Is available to provide you with git repos and stuff Also has ActiveDirectory on git Azure Board Its like Trello or Jira for project management Azure Pipelines Is CI for build and deploy apps Containers on Kubernetes You can implement CI/CD across cloud.</description></item></channel></rss>